const qBank = [
	{
		id: 1,
		question: " Who was the first Indian ruler who had territory outside India?",
		options: [" Ashoka", "Chandragupta Maurya", "Kanishka", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Kanishka",
	},
	{
		id: 2,
		question: "Upnishads are books on :",
		options: ["Politics", "Philosophy", "Social life", "Medicine"],
		answer: "Philosophy",
	},
	{
		id: 3,
		question: "What led to the end of Indus Valley Civilization?",
		options: ["Invasion of Aryans", "Recurrent Floods", "Earthquakes", "All of the above"],
		answer: "All of the above"
	},
	{
		id: 4,
		question: "Who among the following was the first Indian to get selected in ICS (Indian Civil Services)?",
		options: ["Ras Bihari Bose", "Satyendra Nath Tagore", "Devendranath Tagore", "Surendranath Banerjee"],
		answer: "Satyendra Nath Tagore"
	},
	{
		id: 5,
		question: "Gandhiji was involved in a movement in South Africa against which act?",
		options: ["Trade Dispute Act", "Asiatic Registration Act", "Asian employment Act", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Asiatic Registration Act"
	},
	{
		id: 6,
		question: "Which of the following princely states did not accede to the Indian Union after independence?",
		options: ["Telangana", "Hyderabad", "Kashmir", "Jharkhand"],
		answer: "Hyderabad"
	},
    {
		id: 7,
		question: "Who coined the term ‘Satyagraha’?",
		options: ["Sri Aurobindo Ghosh", "Ram Mohan Roy", "Rabindranath Tagore", "Mahatma Gandhi"],
		answer: "Mahatma Gandhi"
	},
	
	{
		id: 8,
		question: "Subhash Chandra Bose became the Supreme Commander of Indian National Army in :",
		options: ["1945", "1943", "1935", "1932"],
		answer: "1943"
	},
	{
		id: 9,
		question: " The Indian National Congress passed Quit India Resolution at :",
		options: ["Ramgarh Session 1940", "Bombay Session 1934", "Wardha Session 1942", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Wardha Session 1942"
	},
	{
		id: 10,
		question: "Whom did Mahatma Gandhi consider his political guru?",
		options: ["Gopal Krishna Gokhale", "Purushottam Das Tandon", "Bal Gangadhar Tilak", "Subhash Chandra Bose"],
		answer: "Gopal Krishna Gokhale"
	},
	{
		id: 11,
		question: "Jallianwala Bagh Massacre in Amritsar took place on :",
		options: ["April 14 1919", "April 13 1919", "May 13 1919", "June 13 1919"],
		answer: "April 13 1919"
	},
	{
		id: 12,
		question: "Which of the following Vedas is rendered musically?",
		options: ["Rig Veda", "Yajur Veda", "Sama Veda", "Atharva Veda"],
		answer: "Sama Veda"
	},
	{
		id: 13,
		question: "The sacred book of Buddhism is called  _______________ .",
		options: ["Agam Sutra", "Tripitaka", "Guru Granth Sahib", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Tripitaka"
	},
	{
		id: 14,
		question: "Who established Nalanda Mahavihara ?",
		options: ["Kumaragupta", "Devgupta", "Skandagupta", "Vedgupta"],
		answer: "Kumaragupta"
	},
	{
		id: 15,
		question: "The Indus Valley Civilisation was a ",
		options: ["Bronze age civilisation", "Chalcolithic age civilisation", "Mesolithic age civilisation", "Neolithic age civilisation"],
		answer: "Bronze age civilisation"
	},
	{
		id: 16,
		question: " ‘Ayurveda’ has its origin in",
		options: ["Rig Veda", "Yajur Veda", "Sama Veda", "Atharva Veda"],
		answer: "Atharva Veda"
	},
	{
		id: 17,
		question: "Vasco da Gama a sailor belongs to _______________ .",
		options: ["German", "Portuguese", "South American", "The Dutch"],
		answer: "Portuguese"
	},
	{
		id: 18,
		question: "The Kailasa temple is one of the largest rock-cut ancient Hindu temple located at Ellora was built by?",
		options: ["Krishndev Rai", "Rajendra Chola", "Krishna I", "Nadivarman"],
		answer: "Krishna I"
	},
	{
		id: 19,
		question: "When was the non-cooperation movement started by M.K Gandhi?",
		options: ["After Rowlatt Act", "Chauri-Chaura incident", "Jalliawalabagh Massacre", "Gandhi Imprisionment"],
		answer: "Jalliawalabagh Massacre"
	},
	{
		id: 20,
		question: "Who is called as “Beacon of light of Asia”",
		options: ["Dr. B.R. Ambedkar", "Subhash Chandra Bose", "Gautam Buddha", "Abdul Gaffer khan"],
		answer: "Subhash Chandra Bose"
	},
	{
		id: 21,
		question: "The Great Bath of Indus Valley civilisation is found at",
		options: ["Harappa", "Mohenjo-Daro", "Kalibangan", "Alamgirpur"],
		answer: "Mohenjo-Daro"
	},
	{
		id: 22,
		question: "_________________ was the founder of Sikhism.",
		options: ["Guru Angad", "Guru Nanak", "Guru Ramdas", "Guru Arjan Dev"],
		answer: "Guru Nanak"
	},
	{
		id: 23,
		question: "The word ‘Veda’ has been derived from the root word ‘Vid’ which means:",
		options: ["Sacredness", "Divinity", "Knowledge", "Doctrine"],
		answer: "Knowledge"
	},
	{
		id: 24,
		question: "Who is known as the Napoleon of India?",
		options: ["Samudragupta", "Srigupta", "Chandragupta", "Skandagupta"],
		answer: "Samudragupta"
	},
	{
		id: 25,
		question: "First Anglo Sikh War fought between _________________ ",
		options: ["The English & French", "The English & king Dalip Singh", "The English & Portuguese", "None of the above"],
		answer: "The English & king Dalip Singh"
	},
]

export default qBank;
